Alessandro Nuzzo

Fascinated from computers since the first Spectrum ZX when I was 8 years old, I've been able to **turn my passion into my job**, studying and improving my programming skills.

Since 2004 I have been working as a web developer and after many years working on PHP I'm studying **functional languages**.

I followed the projects from **analysis of the requirements** to the **workflow organization**, and I've always been fascinated about **agile methodologies**. The study of Scrum, XP and Kanban was source of personal growth and was rich of ideas to improve team workflows.

In my professional career **user groups** had a **fundamental role**. From 1999 to 2003 I actively participated to **Milug** (Milan Linux User Group), organizing meetings and Linuxday editions. In subsequent years, working mainly in PHP, I followed **Grusp** (italian PHP user group) and took part in PHPday. In 2012 I founded the **Milan PHP user group**, managed by myself until 2015.

I put at the disposal of the team my **pragmatic being**, keen on deliver the **Minimum Valuable Product**.



Software Engineering

Via illirico 8, 20133 Milano - Italy

339 8863342 alessandro.nuzzo@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Prima Assicurazioni, Milano — Software Engineering

OCTOBER 2013 - PRESENT

Started working from day one, I developed quite a lot base code both for backend and frontend.

Developed many microservices with Elixir and Phoenix Framework.

In microservices infrastructure I used and studied many technologies like Mysql, PostgreSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ, RESTful web services and GraphQL.

Introduced **React** for frontend development, which I used for the fast quote single page application, reducing the page loading times significantly and improving the user experience.

Developed frontend app using Backbone (2013), Angular (2014), React (2015), React and Redux (2016) and Elm (2017).

Introduced the **agile software development** methods using the SCRUM framework.

Acted as **SCRUM master** in the development team organizing sprint review and retrospective to improve the process and the communication in the team.

Conducted interviews to hire new developers, designing the recruitment process and the technical test.

Always tried to communicate the company commitment for **technological innovation** in an "old" market like insurances one. For this reason I made a speech at CloudConf Turin in 2015, I organized the Erlang Factory Lite 2017 sponsorship in Rome, and I created, involving the rest of the team, our tech blog.

Daily use Docker and AWS.

Facile.it, Milano — Senior Web Developer

MARCH 2013 - OCTOBER 2013

Developed facile.it mobile website in few weeks, within the deadline.

E-one s.r.l., Milano — Senior Software Developer

APRIL 2008 - FEBRUARY 2013

As a php developer in a web agency I developed custom web solutions for different customers, managed the stakeholders and led the development

SKILLS

PHP & symfony ★★★★★

Elixir ★★★★

Elm ★★★★

Mysql ★★★★

GraphQL ★★★★

React & Redux ★★★★

PostgreSQL ***

Redis ★★★★

Docker ★★★★

RabbitMQ ★★★★

Python ★★★★

INTERESTS

Basketball

Whisky

Jazz

Graphic Novels

LANGUAGES

Italiano, mother tongue

English, intermediate

team.

neen s.r.l., Milano — Software Developer

FEBRUARY 2006 - APRIL 2008 Web developer.

EDUCATION

Liceo Scientifico R. Donatelli, Milano — Maturità Scientifica

1995 - 2000

PROJECTS

PHP User Group Milano — Founder and Coordinator

Founder, coordinator and manager, from March 2012 to September 2015, of meetings and events of PHP User Group Milano..